you have always heard in your childhood
that one raised to something is always
one but today I am going to show you
something crazy is it possible to have
one raised to some value like X that
ends up being two this is a tricky
question first of all take natural log
on both sides I will be using log to
denote natural log some people also use
Ln to denote the same you can use
whatever you want to so using this
property of logarithm the X will jump
right here and we get x * log of 1 = log
of 2 now divide both sides by natural
log of one but natural log of one is
zero and we cannot divide by zero so no
real solution exists for X but I told
you this is a tricky question so now how
can we find the complex roots for this
equation we will first start with the
oiler identity which is e raised to I
Theta is equal to cine Theta + I sin
Theta if you are dealing with the
complex world then everyone should know
this identity now if you put the value
of theta as 0o we get cosine 0 + I sin 0
cosine 0 is 1 and sin 0 is 0 so e raised
to i 0 becomes 1 but this also works for
Theta equal 2 pi 4 pi and so on so one
in complex world can be written as e
raised to I * 2 K Pi where k equal 0 1 2
and so on so this x becomes log of 2 /
log of e raised to I * 2 K
Pi we know that log of e raised to a
simply becomes a so this x becomes log
of 2 upon I * 2 K Pi so far so good now
I want this I to be on the top so
multiply and divide by I to get this now
this becomes -1 and therefore X becomes
minus I * log 2 upon 2 K piun but before
we wrap this up we need to make sure
that K is not equal to zero now
surprisingly if you look at Wolfram
Alpha and plug this equation in it you
find that it does not provide any
solution to it now take this X on the
other side and make it as 1 = 2 raed to
1 /x now if you put this equation in
Wolfram Alpha it works and we get the
same solution as what we have proved
before really cool right so good